<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Canada Trip | Kierans Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://TigerWolf.github.io/blog/categories/canada-trip/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://TigerWolf.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-09-23T22:04:18+09:30</updated>
  <id>http://TigerWolf.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Kieran]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Vancouver]]></title>
    <link href="http://TigerWolf.github.io/2009/12/vancouver/"/>
    <updated>2009-12-20T00:00:00+10:30</updated>
    <id>http://TigerWolf.github.io/2009/12/vancouver</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Vancouver is an amazing city. So alive and vibrant. It has an arty feel to it. Its bigger than Adelaide but the main shopping areas felt emptier and less alive compared to say Rundle Mall in Adelaide.</p>

<p>I spent most of my time in Granville St in the Samesun backpackers hostel. It was a great stopover point until my journey up to Whistler. Lots of international visitors and people in similar situations, trying to find themselves in this amazing city.</p>

<p>At night time, the street came alive, with party goers heading to clubs and homeless people in search of donations in return for their various antics, be it card tricks or music made with spoons. Granville St near the backpackers is a dirty street but that gives it that character. It was cleaned up for the Olympics but there was still a lot of construction.</p>

<p>In contrast to this Stanley park is so lush and amazingly beautiful. You are in this busy city and you can walk right into a rain forest and I was amazed at how you could escape to this other world within a city. I really enjoyed the walk around the sea wall that so many Vancouverites make regularly and check out all of the lakes and towering trees that make this place their home.</p>

<p>I almost immediately fell in love with the country&#8217;s most famous sport, Hockey (which we call Ice Hockey). Joining some mates I met at the hostel, when a game was on we ventured to a local pub and followed the game. It was an easy game to pick up and watch.</p>

<p>When it was time to leave this place and venture to my next destination, I hopped on my bus and continued on my journey on the sea to sky highway up through the mountains to Whistler.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Seattle Part 2]]></title>
    <link href="http://TigerWolf.github.io/2009/12/seattle-part-2/"/>
    <updated>2009-12-02T00:00:00+10:30</updated>
    <id>http://TigerWolf.github.io/2009/12/seattle-part-2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<ul>
<li><p><div id='gallery-1' class='gallery galleryid-27 gallery-columns-3 gallery-size-thumbnail'>
<dl class='gallery-item'>
  <dt class='gallery-icon portrait'>
    <a href='http://kieranandrews.com.au/2009/12/seattle-part-2/p1000151_small/'><img width="150" height="150" src="http://kieranandrews.com.au/wp-content/uploads/2009/12/P1000151_small-150x150.gif" class="attachment-thumbnail" alt="P1000151_small" /></a>
  </dt>
</dl></p>

<p><br style='clear: both' />
</div></p></p></li>
</ul>


<p></em></p>

<ul>
<li><p>*</p></li>
<li><p>*</p></li>
</ul>


<p><em>Finally had some time to get my notes and write up about some of my past adventures, more to come!</em></p>

<p>The next day I took the bus into Seattle after figuring it out. Its been a lot harder navigating around here without having internet on my phone as Ive become used to in Australia. Finding my way around Melbourne was easy as I could always pull up a bus timetable or web page about a place I wanted to visit. It was a long trip over the river on the bus but there where some amazing sights and seeing the Seattle skyline was great.</p>

<p>I didnt know where to get off so I got off the biggest station (University St) and started walking around on a quest I would find a shopping area or something interesting. I had a great walk, starting in a rich area with lots of high rise buildings and slowly noticing the places get smaller as I headed towards the coast, where I spotted a soup kitchen. Then I headed sideways up the kill into a China town area and then managed to get back to a different rich area where I could see lots of fancy hotels and fancy shops of big brands id heard of before. I found a monorail and walked along side of it and found my way to the Space Needle!</p>

<p>The space needle was a great, it wasnt very busy. I didnt go up as I didnt see much point.  Right below the space needle there is a science fiction museum and  a music exploration museum focusing on jimmy hendrix. They where both very cool.</p>

<p>The money in america is wierd, $1 notes are crazy and they are just on crappy paper. Also getting used to tips is wierd for me too.</p>

<p>When I was in seattle I also checked out a few shops, the prices in america are awesome but Im saving all of my money up for Whistler. I bought my snowboard in Seattle at snowboard connection. They where heaps friendly and I got an awesome deal, and offered me a beer too! I was there for ages getting the perfect setup. I now have a K2 Darkside (Snowboard), Ride bindings and some sweet K2 boots that are so counfy. Some pics will be up later.</p>

<p>Seattle was awesome and Ill have to go back there some time. Thanks K T for giving me a place to crash and for the awesome ride up to Whistler.</p>

<p>Stay tuned for the next update! VANCOUVER!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Surprise!]]></title>
    <link href="http://TigerWolf.github.io/2009/10/suprise/"/>
    <updated>2009-10-14T00:00:00+10:30</updated>
    <id>http://TigerWolf.github.io/2009/10/suprise</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Wow! Just had the most amazing surprise party pulled on me.</p>

<p>If you didnt know, im heading to Canada on a working holiday for 7 months with a little bit of travel at the start and end to see USA. I have a job as a food station server at the Whistler Blackcomb ski resort in the state of British Columbia.</p>

<p>Without me knowing, my girlfriend Elysia organised a suprise going away party for me! I thought I was going over to join the family for a Sunday dinner when I was greeted by a huge crowd all yelling suprise! I was so shocked I had no idea what to say or do.</p>

<p>It was great to see all of my friends that turned up to wish me well and a few faces I hadn&#8217;t seen in a while. Thanks for coming everyone! There where so many people to chat to and I had a fantastic time.</p>

<p>Not long till I leave now (25th of October). I&#8217;ll be posting more updates as the holiday continues.</p>

<p>That&#8217;s it for now, Kieran</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
