<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Featured | Kierans Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://TigerWolf.github.io/blog/categories/featured/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://TigerWolf.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-09-23T22:06:47+09:30</updated>
  <id>http://TigerWolf.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Kieran]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Codeigniter and Netbeans]]></title>
    <link href="http://TigerWolf.github.io/2010/08/codeigniter-and-netbeans/"/>
    <updated>2010-08-29T00:00:00+09:30</updated>
    <id>http://TigerWolf.github.io/2010/08/codeigniter-and-netbeans</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I have recently stumbled on some really awesome tools, Code Igniter and Netbeans IDE for PHP development. I&#8217;ve used eclipse for Java development through uni and found it really great. After finishing that I found that using eclipse for PHP just was too slow and didn&#8217;t have the right tools for the job.</p>

<p>I used dreamweaver for a while but then stumbled on Netbeans and I am really amazed at how it works and so well. The features I love the most are bracket matching, div matching &#8211; this is where you select a div or bracket and it highlights the end tag or bracket.</p>

<p>It also does really good code highlighting with php and JavaScript and HTML even if they are all in the same file. It&#8217;s not all good though, I found the tag completion annoying and unintuitive so I turned it off but it&#8217;s not a big deal.</p>

<p>Codeigniter is really an amazing PHP framework, it has really sped up my development time and was a great help on a recent project I worked on with a shopping cart. It was really easy to pick up and easy as soon I as understood the whole MVC (Model View Controller) thing, it make a lot of sence to have the database code in the model, the view stuff in the view and then the controller in the middle to handle all of the things inbetween.</p>

<p>I will be definately be using it for a lot more projects and there is a great community support for it with a lot of people using it and backed by a company that also sells a CMS called Expression Engine. Codeigniter 2.0 should be coming out soonish and that will be interesting when it does.</p>

<p>Now that this project is over and im now working on more web design we shall see where it takes me and the interesting discoverys I make along the way.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Seattle Part 2]]></title>
    <link href="http://TigerWolf.github.io/2009/12/seattle-part-2/"/>
    <updated>2009-12-02T00:00:00+10:30</updated>
    <id>http://TigerWolf.github.io/2009/12/seattle-part-2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<ul>
<li><p><div id='gallery-1' class='gallery galleryid-27 gallery-columns-3 gallery-size-thumbnail'>
<dl class='gallery-item'>
  <dt class='gallery-icon portrait'>
    <a href='http://kieranandrews.com.au/2009/12/seattle-part-2/p1000151_small/'><img width="150" height="150" src="http://kieranandrews.com.au/wp-content/uploads/2009/12/P1000151_small-150x150.gif" class="attachment-thumbnail" alt="P1000151_small" /></a>
  </dt>
</dl></p>

<p><br style='clear: both' />
</div></p></p></li>
</ul>


<p></em></p>

<ul>
<li><p>*</p></li>
<li><p>*</p></li>
</ul>


<p><em>Finally had some time to get my notes and write up about some of my past adventures, more to come!</em></p>

<p>The next day I took the bus into Seattle after figuring it out. Its been a lot harder navigating around here without having internet on my phone as Ive become used to in Australia. Finding my way around Melbourne was easy as I could always pull up a bus timetable or web page about a place I wanted to visit. It was a long trip over the river on the bus but there where some amazing sights and seeing the Seattle skyline was great.</p>

<p>I didnt know where to get off so I got off the biggest station (University St) and started walking around on a quest I would find a shopping area or something interesting. I had a great walk, starting in a rich area with lots of high rise buildings and slowly noticing the places get smaller as I headed towards the coast, where I spotted a soup kitchen. Then I headed sideways up the kill into a China town area and then managed to get back to a different rich area where I could see lots of fancy hotels and fancy shops of big brands id heard of before. I found a monorail and walked along side of it and found my way to the Space Needle!</p>

<p>The space needle was a great, it wasnt very busy. I didnt go up as I didnt see much point.  Right below the space needle there is a science fiction museum and  a music exploration museum focusing on jimmy hendrix. They where both very cool.</p>

<p>The money in america is wierd, $1 notes are crazy and they are just on crappy paper. Also getting used to tips is wierd for me too.</p>

<p>When I was in seattle I also checked out a few shops, the prices in america are awesome but Im saving all of my money up for Whistler. I bought my snowboard in Seattle at snowboard connection. They where heaps friendly and I got an awesome deal, and offered me a beer too! I was there for ages getting the perfect setup. I now have a K2 Darkside (Snowboard), Ride bindings and some sweet K2 boots that are so counfy. Some pics will be up later.</p>

<p>Seattle was awesome and Ill have to go back there some time. Thanks K T for giving me a place to crash and for the awesome ride up to Whistler.</p>

<p>Stay tuned for the next update! VANCOUVER!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
